<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learning on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Class!</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/05/12/2021-05-12-dasg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/05/12/2021-05-12-dasg/</guid>
      <description>Data is not neutral, nor are the algorithms that control how the data that governs our lives are used. Interpretations and recommendations made using data are subjective. This course introduces students how to start harnessing the power of data to intelligently cope with the requirements of citizenship, employment, and family to be prepared for a healthy, happy and productive life. In this class students will practice collecting and wrangling data into a usable form, visualizing large data sets to discover patterns, representing data in a meaningful way, exploring varying interpretations of the data and results, and discussing potentials for misuse and abuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI seminar 2/19: Managing data from multiple tables using SQL </title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/13/2019-02-13-intro-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/13/2019-02-13-intro-sql/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Presenter: Robin Donatello, Assistant Professor of Statistics Date: Tuesday February 19th, 2019 Time: 3-3:50 pm Location: Tehama 116 RSVP: http://goo.gl/forms/BnjV0y5zoz09tUU83  Description You’ve got person level data (like country of origin) in one data set, annual data (like income) for each person across multiple years in another data set, but each person is on a team and team characteristics are on yet a THIRD data set. How do you link all this information together to gain any kind of insights?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Coding - Now for credit!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</guid>
      <description>Spring 19 semester is upon us and we&amp;rsquo;re exicted to start up Community Coding again.
 Dates &amp;amp; Times: Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday - 2-4pm Location : Tehama (THMA) 116  What is community coding? Students, staff, faculty, and the public are invited to join our Community Coding sessions. Bring your computer, coding projects, and your questions to this open working environment.
What is this for credit option? Commit to studying 1 hr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Fest Prep</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/23/2018-04-23-data-fest-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/23/2018-04-23-data-fest-prep/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Date: Tuesday April 24, 2018 Time: 2-3:50 pm Location: MLIB 442  Description Planning on participating in Data Fest 2018? Want to practice your data wrangling skills?
On Tuesday we will be doing a &amp;ldquo;dry run&amp;rdquo; of DataFest by using 2017 data. Basically here&amp;rsquo;s the data and the overall analysis goal.
GO! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Using Python for Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/05/2018-04-06-intro_python_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/05/2018-04-06-intro_python_announce/</guid>
      <description>April is Data Fest Prep month! Hone your skills in preparation for this exciting data hackathon event!
Logistics / Setup  Date: Thursday April 12, 2018 Time: 3-3:50 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Edward Roualdes Workshop Materials  Python Notebook HTML version of the notebook    Description In this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore Python and Jupyter notebooks as data analysis tools. The basics of statistical analysis will be focused on Python&amp;rsquo;s library Pandas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Getting Started with Python &amp; Jupyter Notebooks</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/01/2018-04-01-setup_python_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/01/2018-04-01-setup_python_announce/</guid>
      <description>April is Data Fest Prep month! Hone your skills in preparation for this exciting data hackathon event!
Logistics / Setup  Date: Thursday April 5, 2018 Time: 3-3:50 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Grant Esparza [Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials]  The DSI is hosting for our first workshop on Python!
Grant Esparza from Computer Science will help us install Python 3 and the Jupyter Notebook, and get us started using Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Certificate Info Session</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/23/2018-03-23-ds-info-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/23/2018-03-23-ds-info-session/</guid>
      <description>Come learn about the new Undergraduate Certificate in Data Science. Motivation for the program, details about the enrollment process, course requirements and benefits for students. Enrollment in the Certificate program opens Fall 2018.
Thursday 3-29, 2pm, MLIB 442 Community Coding session will follow at 3pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Kick Off Meeting &amp; Intro to R files</title>
      <link>/event/kickoff_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/kickoff_files/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to the DSI slide deck. Materials  Program installation, setup, preferences  NOT COVERED FULLY DURING WORKSHOP   Hands on Introduction to R - Exploring the Data Science Community in Chico.  [Download R code] to download the source code for today.  Opened in a browser window? Right click &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;save as&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;save link as&amp;rdquo;   Save this file to an easy to find place. Desktops are nice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
