<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ChicoState on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/chicostate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ChicoState on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/chicostate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Science info session</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</guid>
      <description>Missed this event? Watch the Video Recording here: [https://media.csuchico.edu/media/0_kkfl6yt8]
 When: Friday, Nov 2nd, noon Where: Butte 101 Do you want to increase your ability to read, understand, create and communicate data as information? To tell a better data story?
Do you want to be a better consumer and curator of news, improving your ability to identify bull-oney stories that are only aimed to spread false information?
Are you concerned about ethics and fairness in algorithms that are used for decisions such as whether or not you get that home mortgage, or that your resume is not tossed out without being seen due to a bias in the screening algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current job and research project openings at Chico State</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/07/11/2018-07-11-student-data-analyst-job-at-chico-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/07/11/2018-07-11-student-data-analyst-job-at-chico-state/</guid>
      <description>Strategic Planning Student Assistant   Department: Office of the President, CSU, Chico
  Project Details: As one of the first steps in the strategic planning process, we are conducting both internal and external scans. The internal scan will review internal data (President’s Listening Tour, Campus Climate Survey, Alumni Attitude Survey, Spring Graduate Survey, etc.) to identify institutional strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats. The external (environmental) scan will examine patterns of change in the surrounding environment that will impact Chico State as an institution in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
