<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DSI on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/dsi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DSI on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/dsi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Community Coding - Now for credit!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</guid>
      <description>Spring 19 semester is upon us and we&amp;rsquo;re exicted to start up Community Coding again.
 Dates &amp;amp; Times: Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday - 2-4pm Location : Tehama (THMA) 116  What is community coding? Students, staff, faculty, and the public are invited to join our Community Coding sessions. Bring your computer, coding projects, and your questions to this open working environment.
What is this for credit option? Commit to studying 1 hr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science info session</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</guid>
      <description>Missed this event? Watch the Video Recording here: [https://media.csuchico.edu/media/0_kkfl6yt8]
 When: Friday, Nov 2nd, noon Where: Butte 101 Do you want to increase your ability to read, understand, create and communicate data as information? To tell a better data story?
Do you want to be a better consumer and curator of news, improving your ability to identify bull-oney stories that are only aimed to spread false information?
Are you concerned about ethics and fairness in algorithms that are used for decisions such as whether or not you get that home mortgage, or that your resume is not tossed out without being seen due to a bias in the screening algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Kick Off Meeting (&amp; quick intro to R)</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/03/24/2017-03-24-dsi-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/03/24/2017-03-24-dsi-kickoff/</guid>
      <description>Logistics  Date: Friday March 24, 2017 Time: 3-4:30 pm Location: MLIB 045  In this kick off session we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what Data Science is, how the Data Science Initiative at Chico State is rising to meet the challenge of preparing and training a much needed computational science workforce, and how you can be a part of it. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll explore who our Data Science community is using R.
Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
