<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>seminar on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/seminar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in seminar on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/seminar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Seminar: Introduction to Bayesian Modeling</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/15/2018-03-15-bayesian-seminar-roualdes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/15/2018-03-15-bayesian-seminar-roualdes/</guid>
      <description>Join us on Thursday March 15 at 3pm in MLIB 442 to hear Dr. Edward Roualdes from Statistics present the benefits of Bayesian Modeling. [RSVP here]
Abstract:  Much of the statistics taught today is more accurately known as frequentist statistics &amp;ndash; a distinction that gets little attention. However, an alternative exists and the alternative bridges what some see as a gap between statisticians and computer scientists who apply mathematical models to data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar: Teaching Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/06/2018-03-06-bioinformatics-class-s18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/06/2018-03-06-bioinformatics-class-s18/</guid>
      <description>Interested in analyzing genomic expression data? Interested in the tools that Biologists use to analyze DNA data?
Join us on Tuesday March 13 at 2pm in MLIB 442 to hear Dr. Gordon Wolfe and Dr. Dave Keller from Biology presenting an overview and update on BIOL 482: Bioinformatics. [RSVP here]
Abstract:  We will present an overview of our BIOL 482 bioinformatics class: how it was developed, and how we see it fulfilling the needs of our curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for speakers and makers</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/08/01/2017-08-01-speakers-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/08/01/2017-08-01-speakers-needed/</guid>
      <description>Looking for speakers for F17 DSI workshops &amp;amp; lightning talks  Is your company or department doing something fun and interesting with Data Science? Do you know a coding tip/trick that you would like to share with the community? Do you have some interesting insights that you would like to share?  Come share your ideas/thoughts/project/insights with the Data Science community
Contact us for more info &amp;amp; to schedule your session.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
