<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>curriculum on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/curriculum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in curriculum on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/curriculum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Science info session</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</guid>
      <description>Missed this event? Watch the Video Recording here: [https://media.csuchico.edu/media/0_kkfl6yt8]
 When: Friday, Nov 2nd, noon Where: Butte 101 Do you want to increase your ability to read, understand, create and communicate data as information? To tell a better data story?
Do you want to be a better consumer and curator of news, improving your ability to identify bull-oney stories that are only aimed to spread false information?
Are you concerned about ethics and fairness in algorithms that are used for decisions such as whether or not you get that home mortgage, or that your resume is not tossed out without being seen due to a bias in the screening algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Undergraduate Certificate in Data Science - Fall 18</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/20/2018-02-21-new-undergraduate-certificate-in-data-science-fall-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/20/2018-02-21-new-undergraduate-certificate-in-data-science-fall-18/</guid>
      <description>We are very proud to share with you that starting Fall 2018 Chico State will offer an Undergraduate Certificate in Data Science!
This certificate program jointly sponsored by the Department of Mathematics and Statistics and the Department of Computer Science introduces students to data science by requiring a set of interdisciplinary classes: applied statistics classes, quantitative classes and computer science (programming and database) classes.
The certificate is designed so that students will gain experience with skills such as inspecting, cleaning, transforming, and modeling data, unstructured data and; computational statistics; pattern recognition; data mining /predictive analytics; machine learning; data visualization; and programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to R (MATH 130)- New section added for spring</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/12/05/2017-12-05-new-intro-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/12/05/2017-12-05-new-intro-to-r/</guid>
      <description>A second section of MATH 130 - Introduction to R has been added to the Spring 18 schedule.
 MW 3-4:45 Holt 155 Week 1-5 only Instructor: Robin Donatello or Edward Roualdes (TBD)  Until open enrollment starts back up in January, contact Robin Donatello to enroll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R Short Course</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/08/14/2017-08-14-introduction-to-r-short-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/08/14/2017-08-14-introduction-to-r-short-course/</guid>
      <description>Learn R Now!  Will you be taking Math 315 (Statistics)? Do you want to have better control over your own data analysis? Have you always wanted to learn R but never got around to it? Do you want to learn how to visualize your data? Are you interested in Data Science, Data Analytics, Business Analytics, Forecasting, Bioinformatics, or Health Informatics? Do you want to learn how to make your research reproducible?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
