<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>community on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in community on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extended hours for Community coding! Spring 20</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/01/22/2020-01-22-spring20-cc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/01/22/2020-01-22-spring20-cc/</guid>
      <description>Hours &amp;amp; Location  MW 10-12, Tehama 116 T 2-4, Butte 518 W 5:30-7pm Butte 518 R 4-6pm Butte 518 F 1-2pm, 3-4pm, Butte 518  Flyer with hours: bit.ly/cc_hours
What is community coding? Taking a programming class this semester? Or a class doing statistical data analysis? Have a pet programming/data science project you’re working on? Students, staff, faculty, and the public are invited to join our Community Coding sessions. Bring your computer, coding projects, and your questions to this open working environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA DataFest 2020 @ Chico State - April 17-19</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/11/07/2019-11-07-asa-datafest-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/11/07/2019-11-07-asa-datafest-2020/</guid>
      <description>Save the Date - April 17-19, 2020! In 2019 Chico State&amp;rsquo;s ASA DataFest tripled the participation from our first year. DataFest 2020 is set to break (our) records! DataFest 2019 hosted 36 undergraduate students in 6 teams, a ton of food and a lot of fun.
This event is open to ALL undergraduates in the North State!
Registration opens January 2020. What is the ASA DataFest?
ASA DataFest is a data hackathon for undergraduate students, sponsored by the American Statistical Association and founded at UCLA, in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA DataFest 2019 @ Chico State - April 5-7</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/17/2019-02-17-asa-datafest-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/17/2019-02-17-asa-datafest-2019/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re doing it again! Last year the ASA DataFest at Chico State featured 12 undergraduate students in 3 teams of 4 people, a ton of food and a lot of fun. This year we&amp;rsquo;re expanding this event, registration is open to ALL undergraduates in the North State! As of 2-17-19 we we already have 22 students (about 5 teams) already registered!
More students means more funding is needed to keep everyone fed, caffinated and to provide excellent prizes to the winners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Coding - Now for credit!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</guid>
      <description>Spring 19 semester is upon us and we&amp;rsquo;re exicted to start up Community Coding again.
 Dates &amp;amp; Times: Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday - 2-4pm Location : Tehama (THMA) 116  What is community coding? Students, staff, faculty, and the public are invited to join our Community Coding sessions. Bring your computer, coding projects, and your questions to this open working environment.
What is this for credit option? Commit to studying 1 hr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science info session</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</guid>
      <description>Missed this event? Watch the Video Recording here: [https://media.csuchico.edu/media/0_kkfl6yt8]
 When: Friday, Nov 2nd, noon Where: Butte 101 Do you want to increase your ability to read, understand, create and communicate data as information? To tell a better data story?
Do you want to be a better consumer and curator of news, improving your ability to identify bull-oney stories that are only aimed to spread false information?
Are you concerned about ethics and fairness in algorithms that are used for decisions such as whether or not you get that home mortgage, or that your resume is not tossed out without being seen due to a bias in the screening algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall hours set for DSI Workshops &amp; Community Coding</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/08/2018-10-01-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/08/2018-10-01-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</guid>
      <description>The Data Science Initative workshops and Community Coding sessions are in full swing for Fall! We secured the same time and place as last semester.
 Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday 2-3:50 Meriam Library (MLIB) 442 (4th floor, directly left out of elevators).
 Workshops &amp;amp; Seminars
 We will be reviewing suggestions from Spring and planning talks and workshops at all levels. Do you have a request for a specialized workshop topic, or want to share your research or project?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar: LabKey Server</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/01/2018-08-19-seminar-labkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/01/2018-08-19-seminar-labkey/</guid>
      <description>The DSI is excited for our first speaker for Fall 2018. Jim Piper has been a regular at our DSI talks and events and is going to share with us his work on LabKey Server, a team collaboration software program specialized for the sciences. A hands demo of this program will be included.
 When: Tuesday October 9th, 2- 2:50pm Where: MLIB 442  Light refreshments will be provided by the DSI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Fest Prep</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/23/2018-04-23-data-fest-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/23/2018-04-23-data-fest-prep/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Date: Tuesday April 24, 2018 Time: 2-3:50 pm Location: MLIB 442  Description Planning on participating in Data Fest 2018? Want to practice your data wrangling skills?
On Tuesday we will be doing a &amp;ldquo;dry run&amp;rdquo; of DataFest by using 2017 data. Basically here&amp;rsquo;s the data and the overall analysis goal.
GO! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the Date! April 27-29 ASA DataFest 2018 @ CSUC</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/21/2018-02-21-asa-datafest-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/21/2018-02-21-asa-datafest-2018/</guid>
      <description>This year the CSU Chico Data Science Initiative will be hosting an ASA DataFest. This will be the first year Chico State has participated.
ASA DataFest is a data hackathon for undergraduate students, sponsored by the American Statistical Association and founded at UCLA, in 2011. A data analysis problem is presented in the form of a dataset and an associated challenge. Teams of students get a dataset on Friday afternoon and work on the problem until Sunday afternoon where they present their findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring hours set for DSI Workshops &amp; Community Coding</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/29/2018-01-29-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/29/2018-01-29-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</guid>
      <description>The Data Science Initative at Chico State and the Chico R Users Group are hosting bi-weekly work sessions and tutorial sessions for the entire campus and Chico community.
 Spring 18: Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday 2-3:50 Meriam Library (MLIB) 442 (4th floor, directly left out of elevators).
 Workshops
 We will be planning a few introductory workshops on topics such as R, Python, Git And a few advanced workshops on creating academic webpages with R Markdown, and an introduction to Bayesian Methods for statistical analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet and analyze data</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/10/24/2017-10-24-meet-and-analyze-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/10/24/2017-10-24-meet-and-analyze-data/</guid>
      <description>The Data Science Initative and the Statistics Faculty are hosting &amp;ldquo;meet and analyze data&amp;rdquo;. This is simply a reserved space held in central locations for people working on code, data analysis, or some other form of Data Science to come, hang out, and code in proximity with other coders. Got a question? We&amp;rsquo;re right there. We may not be able to help directly, but we&amp;rsquo;ll try. At least we&amp;rsquo;ll help you get a good Google search going.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
