<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workshop on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workshop on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sofware Carpentry Workshop for Website Building</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/02/10/2021-02-10-swc-website-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/02/10/2021-02-10-swc-website-march/</guid>
      <description>This event has been postponed due to unforseen and unavoidable circumstances. We will be rescheduling this event for Summer. We are considering expanding the workshop an additional 2 days to include more lessons on R programming. Registered participants want a refund please email datascience@csuchico.edu. We apologize for the inconvenience.
 Ever wish you had a way to showcase your work inside and out of the classroom? A place to share materials with students, or to blog about current research and developments in your field?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Seminar 4/23 &amp; 4/25: Growing a Scientific Mindset to Develop Analytics Teams</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/04/09/2019-04-09-case_study_lyft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/04/09/2019-04-09-case_study_lyft/</guid>
      <description>The Chico State Data Science Initiative is proud to welcome Chico State Alumni Martin Frigaard, App Developer with Intricity and Peter Spangler, Data Scientist at Lyft back for two das to give their invited talk for the Predictive World Analytics 2019 Conference.
Logistics / Setup  Presenters: Martin Frigaard, App Developer with Intricity &amp;amp; Peter Spangler, Data Scientist at Lyft Date/Time (1): Tuesday April 23rd, 2019 - 3:00 pm Date/Time (2): Tuesday April 25rd, 2019 - 2:00 pm Location: Tehama 116 RSVP: http://goo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI seminar 2/19: Managing data from multiple tables using SQL </title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/13/2019-02-13-intro-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/13/2019-02-13-intro-sql/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Presenter: Robin Donatello, Assistant Professor of Statistics Date: Tuesday February 19th, 2019 Time: 3-3:50 pm Location: Tehama 116 RSVP: http://goo.gl/forms/BnjV0y5zoz09tUU83  Description You’ve got person level data (like country of origin) in one data set, annual data (like income) for each person across multiple years in another data set, but each person is on a team and team characteristics are on yet a THIRD data set. How do you link all this information together to gain any kind of insights?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI seminar 2/14: Spatial is Special!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/02/2019-02-02-dsi-seminar-spatial-is-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/02/2019-02-02-dsi-seminar-spatial-is-special/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Presenter: Peter Hansen, Chico State GIS Specialist Date: Thursday February 14th, 2019 Time: 2-2:50 pm Location: Tehama 116 RSVP: http://goo.gl/forms/BnjV0y5zoz09tUU83  Description Are you curious about how to work with or create spatial data? Are you interested in beginning to explore how geographic data can be used in your research and other data inquiries? Data with a spatial component can be analyzed with software called GIS (Geographic Information Systems).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Coding - Now for credit!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</guid>
      <description>Spring 19 semester is upon us and we&amp;rsquo;re exicted to start up Community Coding again.
 Dates &amp;amp; Times: Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday - 2-4pm Location : Tehama (THMA) 116  What is community coding? Students, staff, faculty, and the public are invited to join our Community Coding sessions. Bring your computer, coding projects, and your questions to this open working environment.
What is this for credit option? Commit to studying 1 hr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Carpentry- Post workshop report</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/19/2018-08-19-post-workshop-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/19/2018-08-19-post-workshop-report/</guid>
      <description>Last week Chico State hosted it&amp;rsquo;s first Software Carpentry workshop and it was a great success. We were thrilled to have Reid Otsuji  from UC San Diego and a Library Carpentry instructor come up to help teach the material.
We had three undergraduate students help out as technical assistant roaming helpers throughout the workshop: Grant Esparza (Computer Science), Jerry Tucay (Applied Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics), and Eisley Adoremos (Statistics). Their assistance with answer questions and helping add to the collaborate class notes was invaluable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August Workshop - Reproducible Scientific Research with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/07/14/2018-07-14-swc-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/07/14/2018-07-14-swc-announce/</guid>
      <description>On August 13 - 15th, the DSI is hosting a Software Carpentry workshop for graduate students, faculty, and any other researcher that wants to learn how to conduct reproducible research. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to have any previous knowledge of the tools that will be presented at the workshop.
The Carpentries are a fiscally sponsored project of Community Initiatives. They teach skills that are immediately useful for researchers, using lessons and datasets that allow researchers to quickly apply what they’ve learned to their own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: An Introduction to SAP Predictive Analytics</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/23/2018-04-23-intro-sap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/23/2018-04-23-intro-sap/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Date: Thursday April 26, 2018 Time: 2-2:50 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Dr. Arash Negahban, CSUC College of Business  Description Join us for a peek into the predictive analytics arena from a Business perspective – using the SAP software.This is also a great opportunity to learn about the SAP resources we have available on campus.
SAP Predictive Analytics is the visualization tool for SAP, the world’s largest business software company founded in 1972 and headquartered in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Using Python for Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/05/2018-04-06-intro_python_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/05/2018-04-06-intro_python_announce/</guid>
      <description>April is Data Fest Prep month! Hone your skills in preparation for this exciting data hackathon event!
Logistics / Setup  Date: Thursday April 12, 2018 Time: 3-3:50 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Edward Roualdes Workshop Materials  Python Notebook HTML version of the notebook    Description In this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore Python and Jupyter notebooks as data analysis tools. The basics of statistical analysis will be focused on Python&amp;rsquo;s library Pandas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: A Brief Introduction to Tableau Public</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/04/2018-04-10-intro_tableau_public_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/04/2018-04-10-intro_tableau_public_announce/</guid>
      <description>April is Data Fest Prep month! Hone your skills in preparation for this exciting data hackathon event!
Logistics / Setup  Date: Tuesday April 17, 2018 Time: 2-2:50 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Ben Juliano bjuliano@mail.csuchico.edu Materials: [Slides]  Description This is a hands-on mini-workshop, so bring your laptop if you want to &amp;ldquo;play&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; The why, what, and how of getting into Tableau is presented, including an overview of the Tableau product line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Getting Started with Python &amp; Jupyter Notebooks</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/01/2018-04-01-setup_python_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/01/2018-04-01-setup_python_announce/</guid>
      <description>April is Data Fest Prep month! Hone your skills in preparation for this exciting data hackathon event!
Logistics / Setup  Date: Thursday April 5, 2018 Time: 3-3:50 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Grant Esparza [Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials]  The DSI is hosting for our first workshop on Python!
Grant Esparza from Computer Science will help us install Python 3 and the Jupyter Notebook, and get us started using Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hour of Code: Beyond the Hour</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/12/2018-03-12-gsm-hour-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/12/2018-03-12-gsm-hour-of-code/</guid>
      <description>This is a great way to introduce kids to the joys and power of computing! Note the girls only section as well!
Join us for a workshop that will demystify computer programming and coding through a series of FUN and CREATIVE challenges on WEDNESDAY, MARCH 21. Participants will learn how logic and sequence can be applied to real-world science applications. This workshop is independently paced and picks up at your skill level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Kick Off Meeting (&amp; quick intro to R)</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/03/24/2017-03-24-dsi-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/03/24/2017-03-24-dsi-kickoff/</guid>
      <description>Logistics  Date: Friday March 24, 2017 Time: 3-4:30 pm Location: MLIB 045  In this kick off session we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what Data Science is, how the Data Science Initiative at Chico State is rising to meet the challenge of preparing and training a much needed computational science workforce, and how you can be a part of it. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll explore who our Data Science community is using R.
Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
