<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Carpentry- Post workshop report</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/19/2018-08-19-post-workshop-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/19/2018-08-19-post-workshop-report/</guid>
      <description>Last week Chico State hosted it&amp;rsquo;s first Software Carpentry workshop and it was a great success. We were thrilled to have Reid Otsuji  from UC San Diego and a Library Carpentry instructor come up to help teach the material.
We had three undergraduate students help out as technical assistant roaming helpers throughout the workshop: Grant Esparza (Computer Science), Jerry Tucay (Applied Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics), and Eisley Adoremos (Statistics). Their assistance with answer questions and helping add to the collaborate class notes was invaluable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August Workshop - Reproducible Scientific Research with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/07/14/2018-07-14-swc-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/07/14/2018-07-14-swc-announce/</guid>
      <description>On August 13 - 15th, the DSI is hosting a Software Carpentry workshop for graduate students, faculty, and any other researcher that wants to learn how to conduct reproducible research. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to have any previous knowledge of the tools that will be presented at the workshop.
The Carpentries are a fiscally sponsored project of Community Initiatives. They teach skills that are immediately useful for researchers, using lessons and datasets that allow researchers to quickly apply what they’ve learned to their own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Data Visualization with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/18/2018-04-19-ggplot2_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/18/2018-04-19-ggplot2_announce/</guid>
      <description>April is Data Fest Prep month! Hone your skills in preparation for this exciting data hackathon event!
Logistics / Setup  Date: Thursday April 18, 2018 Time: 3-3:45 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Robin Donatello: rdonatello@csuchico.edu Materials: R code (solutions will be posted after the workshop!)  Details  Are you new to R and want to learn how to make data visualization? Are you new to ggplot and want to understand more how the syntax works?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to R (MATH 130)- New section added for spring</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/12/05/2017-12-05-new-intro-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/12/05/2017-12-05-new-intro-to-r/</guid>
      <description>A second section of MATH 130 - Introduction to R has been added to the Spring 18 schedule.
 MW 3-4:45 Holt 155 Week 1-5 only Instructor: Robin Donatello or Edward Roualdes (TBD)  Until open enrollment starts back up in January, contact Robin Donatello to enroll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R Short Course</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/08/14/2017-08-14-introduction-to-r-short-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/08/14/2017-08-14-introduction-to-r-short-course/</guid>
      <description>Learn R Now!  Will you be taking Math 315 (Statistics)? Do you want to have better control over your own data analysis? Have you always wanted to learn R but never got around to it? Do you want to learn how to visualize your data? Are you interested in Data Science, Data Analytics, Business Analytics, Forecasting, Bioinformatics, or Health Informatics? Do you want to learn how to make your research reproducible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Workshop - Fitting introductory statistical models in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/28/2017-04-28-stat-models-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/28/2017-04-28-stat-models-announce/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Date: Friday April 28, 2017 Time: 3-4:30 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Robin Donatello: rdonatello@csuchico.edu [Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials]  Learning Objectives In this workshop you will learn and practice the following:
 How to conduct a handful of statistical analysis techniques using R  Note: This workshop does not cover the Statistical Methodology or theory behind these statistical procedures. This workshop assumes that you have checked model assumptions and have chosen the most appropriate model for the research question being analyzed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Workshop - Data Visualization with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/21/2017-04-21-ggplot2_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/21/2017-04-21-ggplot2_announce/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Date: Friday April 21, 2017 Time: 3-4:30 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Robin Donatello: rdonatello@csuchico.edu [Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials]  Learning Objectives In this workshop you will explore data through visual tools using ggplot. You will learn how to plot different graphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Workshop - Exploring your data</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/14/2017-04-14-import_data_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/14/2017-04-14-import_data_announce/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Date: Friday April 14, 2017 Time: 3-4:30 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Robin Donatello: rdonatello@csuchico.edu  Learning Objectives In this workshop you will learn and practice the following:
 How to get data into R from a variety of places including the web, from excel, from a CSV file and from a simple text file. How to start looking at your data using tables and simple plots Identifying problems in the data such as missing data or numbers stored as characters  Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Workshop - Preparing Data for Analysis using R</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/07/2017-04-07-tidy_announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/07/2017-04-07-tidy_announce/</guid>
      <description>Logistics  MLIB 442 3PM - 4:30M(+) Friday April 7, 2017 Dr. Rick Hubbard  Are Your Data Tidy? Or, untidy? Before data can be modeled, analyzed or interpreted&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;data must be accessible in meaning-laden forms.
Annually, many Analysts around the globe report expending up to 80% of the effort and duration of an investigation in &amp;ldquo;wrangling&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;tidying&amp;rdquo; data into a &amp;ldquo;shape&amp;rdquo; that enables thoughtful, economical analysis. Does this sound like one of your projects?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Kick Off Meeting &amp; Intro to R files</title>
      <link>/event/kickoff_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/kickoff_files/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to the DSI slide deck. Materials  Program installation, setup, preferences  NOT COVERED FULLY DURING WORKSHOP   Hands on Introduction to R - Exploring the Data Science Community in Chico.  [Download R code] to download the source code for today.  Opened in a browser window? Right click &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;save as&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;save link as&amp;rdquo;   Save this file to an easy to find place. Desktops are nice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
