<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>event on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in event on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Norcon - Hacker Conference April 13th</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/04/08/2019-04-08-norcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/04/08/2019-04-08-norcon/</guid>
      <description>Chico&amp;rsquo;s one and only hacker con. By hackers, for hackers. The Norcon Security Conference is a one-day event created by and intended for the community. This is the place where security professionals, hobbyists, and anyone interested in security can come to hang out. Norcon features lectures and interactive training aimed at varying skill levels. Everyone at Norcon is encouraged to participate and learn. We embrace those from diverse backgrounds, ages, and skill levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in Data Science technical conference! Mon Mar 4th, Sylvesters 100</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/23/2019-02-23-wids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/23/2019-02-23-wids/</guid>
      <description>One day technical conference The Global Women in Data Science (WiDS) Conference aims to inspire and educate data scientists worldwide, regardless of gender, and support women in the field. This annual one-day technical conference provides an opportunity to hear about the latest data science related research and applications in a broad set of domains, All genders are invited to participate in the conference, which features outstanding women doing outstanding work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI seminar 2/19: Managing data from multiple tables using SQL </title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/13/2019-02-13-intro-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/13/2019-02-13-intro-sql/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Presenter: Robin Donatello, Assistant Professor of Statistics Date: Tuesday February 19th, 2019 Time: 3-3:50 pm Location: Tehama 116 RSVP: http://goo.gl/forms/BnjV0y5zoz09tUU83  Description You’ve got person level data (like country of origin) in one data set, annual data (like income) for each person across multiple years in another data set, but each person is on a team and team characteristics are on yet a THIRD data set. How do you link all this information together to gain any kind of insights?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Coding - Now for credit!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/21/2019-01-21-community-coding-now-for-credit/</guid>
      <description>Spring 19 semester is upon us and we&amp;rsquo;re exicted to start up Community Coding again.
 Dates &amp;amp; Times: Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday - 2-4pm Location : Tehama (THMA) 116  What is community coding? Students, staff, faculty, and the public are invited to join our Community Coding sessions. Bring your computer, coding projects, and your questions to this open working environment.
What is this for credit option? Commit to studying 1 hr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science info session</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/29/2018-10-29-ds-info-session-f18/</guid>
      <description>Missed this event? Watch the Video Recording here: [https://media.csuchico.edu/media/0_kkfl6yt8]
 When: Friday, Nov 2nd, noon Where: Butte 101 Do you want to increase your ability to read, understand, create and communicate data as information? To tell a better data story?
Do you want to be a better consumer and curator of news, improving your ability to identify bull-oney stories that are only aimed to spread false information?
Are you concerned about ethics and fairness in algorithms that are used for decisions such as whether or not you get that home mortgage, or that your resume is not tossed out without being seen due to a bias in the screening algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar: LabKey Server</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/01/2018-08-19-seminar-labkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/01/2018-08-19-seminar-labkey/</guid>
      <description>The DSI is excited for our first speaker for Fall 2018. Jim Piper has been a regular at our DSI talks and events and is going to share with us his work on LabKey Server, a team collaboration software program specialized for the sciences. A hands demo of this program will be included.
 When: Tuesday October 9th, 2- 2:50pm Where: MLIB 442  Light refreshments will be provided by the DSI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Carpentry- Post workshop report</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/19/2018-08-19-post-workshop-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/19/2018-08-19-post-workshop-report/</guid>
      <description>Last week Chico State hosted it&amp;rsquo;s first Software Carpentry workshop and it was a great success. We were thrilled to have Reid Otsuji  from UC San Diego and a Library Carpentry instructor come up to help teach the material.
We had three undergraduate students help out as technical assistant roaming helpers throughout the workshop: Grant Esparza (Computer Science), Jerry Tucay (Applied Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics), and Eisley Adoremos (Statistics). Their assistance with answer questions and helping add to the collaborate class notes was invaluable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataFest Registration now open!</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/26/2018-03-26-datafest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/26/2018-03-26-datafest/</guid>
      <description>Click here to Register  Tackle a substantial real-world problem Hone your computational and statistical skills Free food Network with local industry partners Friendly competition - win swag and bragging rights! Prep workshops leading up to the event - up your coding skills in our pre-event workshops  Registration closes on April 14th. (Two weeks prior to the event) This is so we can ensure there will be enough food and prizes for everyone!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
