<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>analysis on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in analysis on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paid summer research opportunity- Basic needs and food insecurity among college students</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/04/07/2021-04-07-csc2-chc-2021-ugr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/04/07/2021-04-07-csc2-chc-2021-ugr/</guid>
      <description>The Chico STEM connections collaborative (CSC2) offers a summer undergraduate research program (UGR Program) to eligible students who are at least in their second semester of their sophomore year. Students are eligible to participate in CSC² programs and services if they are:
 Hispanic, or first generation college student, or low income, AND Enrolled as a student in one of these majors.  The Center for Healthy Communities is partnering with the Data Science Initiative to host 1-2 students to research basic needs and food insecurity among college students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in Data Science technical conference! Mon Mar 4th, Sylvesters 100</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/23/2019-02-23-wids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/23/2019-02-23-wids/</guid>
      <description>One day technical conference The Global Women in Data Science (WiDS) Conference aims to inspire and educate data scientists worldwide, regardless of gender, and support women in the field. This annual one-day technical conference provides an opportunity to hear about the latest data science related research and applications in a broad set of domains, All genders are invited to participate in the conference, which features outstanding women doing outstanding work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSI Workshop - Fitting introductory statistical models in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/28/2017-04-28-stat-models-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/28/2017-04-28-stat-models-announce/</guid>
      <description>Logistics / Setup  Date: Friday April 28, 2017 Time: 3-4:30 pm Location: MLIB 442 Presenter: Robin Donatello: rdonatello@csuchico.edu [Workshop Details &amp;amp; Materials]  Learning Objectives In this workshop you will learn and practice the following:
 How to conduct a handful of statistical analysis techniques using R  Note: This workshop does not cover the Statistical Methodology or theory behind these statistical procedures. This workshop assumes that you have checked model assumptions and have chosen the most appropriate model for the research question being analyzed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
