<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ASA DataFest 2020 @ Chico State - April 17-19</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/11/07/2019-11-07-asa-datafest-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/11/07/2019-11-07-asa-datafest-2020/</guid>
      <description>Save the Date - April 17-19, 2020! In 2019 Chico State&amp;rsquo;s ASA DataFest tripled the participation from our first year. DataFest 2020 is set to break (our) records! DataFest 2019 hosted 36 undergraduate students in 6 teams, a ton of food and a lot of fun.
This event is open to ALL undergraduates in the North State!
Registration opens January 2020. What is the ASA DataFest?
ASA DataFest is a data hackathon for undergraduate students, sponsored by the American Statistical Association and founded at UCLA, in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA DataFest 2019 @ Chico State - April 5-7</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/17/2019-02-17-asa-datafest-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/17/2019-02-17-asa-datafest-2019/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re doing it again! Last year the ASA DataFest at Chico State featured 12 undergraduate students in 3 teams of 4 people, a ton of food and a lot of fun. This year we&amp;rsquo;re expanding this event, registration is open to ALL undergraduates in the North State! As of 2-17-19 we we already have 22 students (about 5 teams) already registered!
More students means more funding is needed to keep everyone fed, caffinated and to provide excellent prizes to the winners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the Date! April 27-29 ASA DataFest 2018 @ CSUC</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/21/2018-02-21-asa-datafest-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/21/2018-02-21-asa-datafest-2018/</guid>
      <description>This year the CSU Chico Data Science Initiative will be hosting an ASA DataFest. This will be the first year Chico State has participated.
ASA DataFest is a data hackathon for undergraduate students, sponsored by the American Statistical Association and founded at UCLA, in 2011. A data analysis problem is presented in the form of a dataset and an associated challenge. Teams of students get a dataset on Friday afternoon and work on the problem until Sunday afternoon where they present their findings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
