<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DSI on Chico State DSI Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/dsi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DSI on Chico State DSI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/dsi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fall hours set for DSI Workshops &amp; Community Coding</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/08/2018-10-01-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/08/2018-10-01-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</guid>
      <description>The Data Science Initative workshops and Community Coding sessions are in full swing for Fall! We secured the same time and place as last semester.
 Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday 2-3:50 Meriam Library (MLIB) 442 (4th floor, directly left out of elevators).
 Workshops &amp;amp; Seminars
 We will be reviewing suggestions from Spring and planning talks and workshops at all levels. Do you have a request for a specialized workshop topic, or want to share your research or project?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Undergraduate Certificate in Data Science - Fall 18</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/20/2018-02-21-new-undergraduate-certificate-in-data-science-fall-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/20/2018-02-21-new-undergraduate-certificate-in-data-science-fall-18/</guid>
      <description>We are very proud to share with you that starting Fall 2018 Chico State will offer an Undergraduate Certificate in Data Science!
This certificate program jointly sponsored by the Department of Mathematics and Statistics and the Department of Computer Science introduces students to data science by requiring a set of interdisciplinary classes: applied statistics classes, quantitative classes and computer science (programming and database) classes.
The certificate is designed so that students will gain experience with skills such as inspecting, cleaning, transforming, and modeling data, unstructured data and; computational statistics; pattern recognition; data mining /predictive analytics; machine learning; data visualization; and programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring hours set for DSI Workshops &amp; Community Coding</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/29/2018-01-29-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/29/2018-01-29-dsi-workshops-community-coding/</guid>
      <description>The Data Science Initative at Chico State and the Chico R Users Group are hosting bi-weekly work sessions and tutorial sessions for the entire campus and Chico community.
 Spring 18: Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday 2-3:50 Meriam Library (MLIB) 442 (4th floor, directly left out of elevators).
 Workshops
 We will be planning a few introductory workshops on topics such as R, Python, Git And a few advanced workshops on creating academic webpages with R Markdown, and an introduction to Bayesian Methods for statistical analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
